GLTBQ.2013.03
GLBTQ Archives
History 301 Oral History Project
2002
GLTBQ.2013.03
GLBTQ Archives
1.5 Linear feet
In the fall of 2002, Professor Katherine Hermes offered a course in the history department called, “The Historical Imagination” (History 301). The GLBTQ Archives, then known as the Gender Equity Archive, was a main source for the class. Interviewees for an oral history project were chosen from notable activists represented in the archives. The collection is comprised of these interviews.
Belliveau, Robert
Bonelli, John
Brill, Helen
Brown, Keith
Cardarelli, Richard
Denman, Timothy
Dyton, Regina
Estabrook, Linda
Gabel-Brett, Carolyn
Gooder, Maryanne (William)
Hadlock, Jennifer
Hanley, James
Howell, Ruth
Jones, Clinton R
Kinlock, Charlotte
Kissling, Albert
McHaelen, Robin
Nelson, Richard
Pattee, Christine
Stanback, Anne
Stillson, Richard
Thomas, Mel
Wrobel, Loretta
Related Archival Materials note
Many interviewees worked for organizations represented in the GLTBQ Archives at the Elihu Burritt Library. These include but are not limited to: CT Colation for LGBT Civil Rights, Connecticut Lesibian and Gay PRIDE Festival, and the Hartford Gay and Lesbian Health Collective.
Existence and Location of Copies note
Most of the oral history interviews present in the collection are available within the Digital Collections of the Elihu Burritt Library at Central Connecticut State University.
Biographical/Historical note
In the fall of 2002, Professor Katherine Hermes offered a course in the history department called, “The Historical Imagination” (History 301). Its focus was on how history is written and interpreted. While the course centered on questions key to working historians, the chosen topic for addressing these issues was the history of sex and sexuality. The GLBTQ Archives, then known as the Gender Equity Archive, was a main source for the class.
Included in the syllabus was an oral history project in which the students were to interview a person who had somehow been involved in the gay community. Many interviewees were chosen from gay activists living in and around Hartford. The interviews were conducted within the last week of October and first week of November, 2002. Most of the interviews have been digitized and are available within the digital collections of the Elihu Burritt Library.
Because most of the people interviewed for the project are represented somewhere else in the GLBTQ Archives, there is much interconnected archival material. Many interviewees mention one another in the interviews.
Scope and Contents note
While the syllabus and project description of the class History 301 is part of the collection, the majority of the materials are the oral histories that the class collected. Most of the interviews can now be accessed through the Digital Collections of the Elihu Burrit Library at Central Connecticut State University. DVDs of the interviews are present in the collection.
Arrangement note
The collection is organized into three series: Information about the History 301 course, Administrative information about each of the interviews, and the Interviews themselves, originally recorded on VHS tapes, which were transferred to DVDs.
AIDS (Disease) -- Social aspects.; AIDS activists -- United States; Community health services; Community health services -- Connecticut; Connecticut Stonewall Foundation; connecticut womens rights; Dignity/Hartford; Gay and lesbian studies; Gay clergy; Gay community -- Connecticut; Gay couples -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States; Gay liberation movement -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Gay pride parades; Gay rights -- United States -- History; Gays -- Connecticut -- Exhibitions; Homosexuality -- Families; Homosexuality -- United States.; Homosexuality and education -- Connecticut; Homosexuality--Religious aspects--Catholic Church; Interviews; Lesbians -- Connecticut; Oral History; Same-sex marriage -- Connecticut; Women -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Women's music festivals.
- History 301 [Syllabus, project description, correspondence], 2002
  - Syllabus and project description, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence relating to project, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lists of interviewees and possibilities of interviewees; interviewers' reports, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Administrative information, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Ault, Franci Anne, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Belliveau, Robert, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bonelli, John, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brill, Helen, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brown, Keith, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cardarelli, Richard, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dyton, Regina, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Estabrook, Linda, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Gabel, Carolyn, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Gale, Carol, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hadlock, Jennifer, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hanley, James, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Howell, Ruth, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Jones, Rev. Camon Clinton, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Gooder, Maryanne (William A.), 2002 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Kinlock, Charlotte M., 2002 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Kissling, Albert, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - McHaelen, Robin, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Nelson, Richard and Denman, Timothy, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Pattee, Christine, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Stillson, Richard, Ph.D., 2002 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Thomas, Mel, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Wrobel, Loretta, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- DVDs and VCR tapes of interviews, 2002
  - Belliveau, Robert [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 1)
  - Bonelli, John [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 2)
  - Brill, Helen [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 3)
  - Brown, Keith [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 4)
  - Cardarelli, Richard [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 5)
  - Dyton, Regina [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 7)
  - Gabel, Carolyn [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 8)
  - Gale, Carol [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 9)
  - Gooder, Maryanne (William A.) [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 22)
  - Hadlock, Jennifer [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 10)
  - Hanley, James [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 11)
  - Howell, Ruth [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 12)
  - Jones, Canon Clinton [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 13)
  - Kinlock, Charlotte and Stanback, Anne [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 14)
  - Kissling, Albert [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 15)
  - McHaelen, Robin [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 16)
  - Nelson, Richard and Denman, Timothy [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 17)
  - Pattee, Christine [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 18)
  - Stillson, Richard [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 19)
  - Thomas, Mel [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 20)
  - Wrobel, Loretta [DVD], 2002 (Box 1, Object 21)
  - Howell, Ruth [cassette tape], 2002 (Box 1, Object 23)
  - Belliveau, Robert [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 1)
  - Bonelli, John [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 2)
  - Brill, Helen [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 3)
  - Brown, Keith [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 4)
  - Cardarelli, Richard [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 5)
  - Dyton, Regina [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 6)
  - Estabrook, Linda, 2002 (Box 2, Object 7)
  - Gabel, Carolyn [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 8)
  - Gale, Carol [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 9)
  - Gooder, Maryanne (William A.) [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 22)
  - Hadlock, Jennifer [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 10)
  - Hanley, James [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 11)
  - Howell, Ruth [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 12)
  - Jones, Canon Clinton [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 13)
  - Kinlock, Charlotte and Stanback, Anne [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 14)
  - Kissling, Albert [VCR], 2002 (Bin 2, Object 15)
  - Nelson, Richard and Denman, Timothy [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 17)
  - Pattee, Christine [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Map-case 18)
  - Stillson, Richard [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 19)
  - Thomas, Mel [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 20)
  - Wrobel, Loretta [VCR], 2002 (Box 2, Object 21)
  - Composite tape using interviews from Stillson, Thomas, Gabel, Gale, and Howell for Diversity Week, April 21, 2003 (Box 2, Object 23)